<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="DialReadingActivity"><![CDATA[<p><b>Dial Reading Help</b></p>
        <p>Follow the instructions on the Dial Reading screen.</p>]]></string>



    <string name="ContinousSetupActivity"><![CDATA[<p><b>Continuous Observation Setup Help</b></p>
        <p><u>Data Output Rate</u>: Sets the rate at which data are archived and the screen is updated.</p>
        <p><u>Filter Time Constant</u>: Sets the time constant of a three stage RC filter in seconds.</p>
        <p>Data Output Rate and Filter Time Constant must be chosen to satisfy the Nyquist Criterion 
        to prevent aliasing.  Choose values such that the Data Output Rate is at least twice the Filter Time Constant.
        </p>]]></string>



    <string name="StationDetailsActivity"><![CDATA[<p><b>Station Details</b></p>
        <p>This screen permits editing or deleting the seleted station. To edit the station data, tap on 
        the Pencil icon in the top right corner of the screen. To delete it, tap on the Trash can icon</p>
        <p><u>Station ID</u>: Name of the station.</p> 
        <p><u>Observer ID</u>: Name of the observer or any other information you wish to be included with 
        the data.</p>
        <p><u>Latitude</u>: Decimal degrees, positive North. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Longitude</u>: Decimal degrees, positive East. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Elevation</u>: Elevation of the station, in meters. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Meter Height</u>: Height of the gravimeter above the station, in meters. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Enable Earth Tide</u>: Indicates whether Earth Tide corrections are enabled for this station. 
        When they are enabled, they will be added to the Observed Gravity reading during Single 
        Observations.</p>]]></string>

    <!--     Activities W/ Fragments -->
    <string name="FileSelectActivity"><![CDATA[<p>File Select</p><p></p>]]></string>
    <string name="StationListActivity"><![CDATA[<p>Stations</p><p></p>]]></string>

    <!--   Fragments Help Text -->
    <string name="FileSelectFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>File Select Help</b></p>
        <p>Select a file for the curent operation. If you are not in the correct directory, use the Up button 
        to go up in the directory tree, or tap on a directory name to go down into it. When you find the file 
        you are looking for, tap on it.</p>
        <p>If you are creating a new file, tap on the Create New File button.</p>]]></string>

    <!--     Settings Fragments -->
    <string name="SystemParamsFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>System Parameters Help</b></p>
        <p><u>Use non-calibrated points</u>: When this checkbox is checked, the dial value may be set to 
        a non-calibrated point, meaning other than a multiple of 50 units. When it is unchecked, only 
        multiples of 50 units may be used.</p>
        <p><u>New Dial Reading</u>: Permits synchronizing the gravimeter dial reading and this application. 
        Only integer values between 250 and 6850 are accepted.</p>
        <p><u>Feed Back Gain</u>: Permits adjusting the sensitivity of the feedback. Lowering the gain 
        increases accuracy at the expense of reading time and vice versa.</p>
        <p><u>Observation Precision</u>: Adjusts the desired precision at which a reading will be accepted. 
        A lower precision decreases reading time and vice versa.</p>
        <p><u>Enable Station Select</u>: When this checkbox is checked, the user is able to select a station 
        for an observation. When it is unchecked, the /"default/" station parameters are used. Leaving 
        this selection un-checked will simplify observations by eliminating the station select screen.</p>
        <p><u>Meter Connection</u>: Displays connection type, device name and connection status.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="MeterParamsFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Meter Parameters Help</b></p>
        <p><u>Reading Line</u>: The dial reading value at which the beam is null when the duty cycle is set 
        to 50%.</p>
        <p><u>Beam Scale</u>: This is a scaling factor used to convert the beam position to mGal.</p>
        <p><u>Feedback Scale</u>: This is a scaling factor used to convert the feedback signal to mGal.</p>
        <p><u>Minimum Stop</u>: The dial setting at which the beam is on the bottom stop.</p>
        <p><u>Maximum Stop</u>: The dial setting at which the beam is on the top stop.</p>
        <p>These parameters need to be verified and updated from time to time. Instructions for doing so are 
        detailed in the manual.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="LevelParamsFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Level Parameters Help</b></p><p>These are the parameters 
        required to model the level correction. They may be determined and updated at any time. See the manual for details.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="StationListFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Stations Help</b></p><p>This screen permits adding
        a station or selecting one whose parameters will be used for the observation.</p>
        <p>The Default station is used in all cases when the Enable Station Select checkbox in the System 
        Parameters screen is unchecked. This station may be edited but it may not be deleted.</p><p>Stations
        can be exported to and imported from a CSV (comma separated value) file. The fields are ordered in
        the file in the same order as they appear on the screen and as shown below:</p>
        <p>Station ID, Observer ID, Latitude, Longitude, Duty Cycle, Elevation, Height, Enable Earthtide</p>]]></string>

    <string name="SurveyTemplateListFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Survey Templates Help</b></p><p>This screen
        permits adding a survey template or selecting one whose parameters will be used to create a survey.</p>
        <p></p><p>Survey templates can be exported to and imported from a CSV (comma separated value) file.
        The fields are ordered in the file in the same order as they appear on the screen and as shown below:</p>
        <p>Survey ID, Client Name, Observer ID, Latitude, Longitude, Elevation, Height, Duty Cycle, Initial Line Number,
        Line Orientation, Initial Station Number, Station Orientation, Station Spacing, Station Update Direction,
        Enable Station Number Auto Update, Enable Reverse Station Update Direction for New Lines, Enable Earthtide</p>]]></string>

    <string name="StationEditFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Station Edit Help</b></p>
        <p><u>Station ID</u>: Name of the station.</p> 
        <p><u>Observer ID</u>: Name of the observer or any other information you wish to be included with 
        the data.</p>
        <p><u>Latitude</u>: Decimal degrees, positive North. Leave Blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Longitude</u>: Decimal degrees, positive East. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Elevation</u>: Elevation of the station, in meters. Leave blank or zero if unavailable.</p>
        <p><u>Meter Height</u>: Height of the gravimeter above the station, in meters.</p>
        <p><u>Enable Earth Tide (Checkbox)</u>: When checked the value of the Earth Tide correction (Longman) 
        will be added to observed gravity. This applies to single observation mode only. If BOTH latitude 
        and longitude are zero or blank no Earth Tide will be calculated. Note that both Latitude and Longitude 
        must be zero to indicate that no coordinates are available.</p>
        <p><u>Obtain Lat/Long from GPS (Button)</u>: Retrieves the latitude and longitude data from the Android 
        device\'s internal GPS receiver.</p>]]></string>

    <!--     Setup Fragments -->
    <string name="ReadMeterFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Read Meter and Set Duty Cycle Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to set the feedback force to a fixed value and displays the various 
        outputs from the gravity sensor. This is useful for certain calibration procedures. You will 
        see the effect of a new duty cycle value only after you have started a reading. You can send 
        new duty cycle values to the meter as needed.</p>

        <p><b>New Duty Cycle</b>: Enter a new duty cycle value, between 5 and 98, then tap the Set button.</p>
        <p><b>Set</b>: Sends the New Duty Cycle value to the meter.</p>
        <p><b>Start Reading</b>: This button tells the meter to start sending gravity data in one second 
        intervals. This data is displayed in the fields at the top of the screen. The reading will be 
        terminated when you leave this tab.</p>]]></string>


    <!--     >>Further instructions to be supplied by Keisuke.<< </p> -->
    <string name="StopsReadingLineFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Set Stops and Reading Line Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to determine the meter\'s maximum and minimum stops and reading line.        
         Refer to Chapter Five, Adjusting Beam Stops in the manual. </p>

        <p><b>10\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 10\%%.</p>
        <p><b>50\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 50\%%.</p>
        <p><b>90\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 90\%%.</p>
        <p><b>New Duty Cycle</b>: Enter a new duty cycle value, between 5 and 98, then tap the Set button.</p>
        <p><b>Set</b>: Sends the New Duty Cycle value to the meter.</p>
        <p><b>Start Reading</b>: This button tells the meter to start sending gravity data in one second 
        intervals, which will be displayed in the Beam Frequency field. The reading will be 
        terminated when you leave this tab.</p>
        <p><b>Accept</b>: Stores the Maximum and Minimum Stops and Reading Line values in the application 
        database. They can be viewed in the Meter Parameters screen.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="CalculateBeamScaleFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Calculate Beam Scale Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to determine the meter\'s beam scale value.         
        See Chapter Five, Calculate Beam Scale Factor in the manual. </p>

        <p><b>50\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 50\%%.</p>
        <p><b>Base Dial Reading</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Base DR -0.250 mGal</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Base DR +0.250 mGal</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>-0.250 Beam Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>+0.250 Beam Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Delta Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Beam Scale</b>: The calculated beam scale value.</p>
        <p><b>Start Reading</b>: This button tells the meter to start sending gravity data in one second 
        intervals, which will be displayed in the Beam Frequency field. The reading will be 
        terminated when you leave this tab.</p>
        <p><b>Accept</b>: Stores the Beam Scale value in the application database. It can be viewed in 
        the Meter Parameters screen.</p>]]></string>

    <!--     Options Fragments -->
    <string name="OutputObsDataFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Output Observation Data Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to manage the observation data. Data may be saved on the Android device\'s 
        internal SD card for uploading to a computer using the Save buttons, or deleted from the application\'s 
        internal database with the Delete buttons.</p>
        <p>The data is sent in CSV (comma separated values) format. This format is suitable for direct input 
        into spread sheets and other programs. The data is not automatically deleted after an upload; you must 
        use the delete buttons to delete unwanted data. New data is always appended to the end of existing 
        data. The number of records stored in the application\'s internal database is displayed at the top of 
        the screen.</p>
        <p><b>Single Mode Data File</b>: Single Mode observation data records consist of 20 fields. They are 
        saved in the following order: Station ID, ObserverID, Meter Serial Number, Date, Time, Observed gravity, 
        Dial Reading, Feedback Correction, Earth Tide Correction, Level Correction, Temperature Correction, 
        Beam Error, Meter Height, Elevation, Latitude, Longitude, Elapsed Time, Standard Deviation, Temperature 
        Frequency, Note.</p>
        <p><b>Continuous Mode Data File</b>: Continuous Mode observation data can be saved as either 
        short or long records. Short records consist of 9 fields. They are saved in the following order: Date, 
        Time, Observed Gravity, Dial Reading, Feedback Correction, Earth Tide Value, Level Correction, 
        Temperature Correction and Note.</p>
        <p>Long records consist of 23 fields. They are saved in the following order: Date, Time, Observed Gravity, Dial, 
        Feedback Correction, Earth Tide Correction, Level Correction, Temperature Correction, Station ID, 
        Observer ID, Meter Serial Number, Height, Elevation, Latitude, Longitude, Elapsed Time, Data Output 
        Rate, Filter Time Constant, Temperature Frequency, Beam Frequency, Cross Level Frequency, Long Level 
        Frequency, Note.</p>
        <p>The units for the data are shown in the table below.</p>
        <p><table>
             <tr> 
               <td style="width:100px"><b>Field</b></td>
               <td style="width:200px"><b>Units</b></td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Gravity</td>
               <td>mGals</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Elevation</td>
               <td>meters</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Height</td>
               <td>meters</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Latitude</td>
               <td>degrees (decimal) positive North</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Longitude</td>
               <td>degrees (decimal) positive East</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Date</td>
               <td>yyyy/mm/ss</td>
             </tr>
             <tr>
               <td>Time</td>
               <td>hh:mm:ss</td>
             </tr>
           </table></p>]]></string>

    <string name="ViewObsDataFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>View Observation Data Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to view the observation data stored in the application\'s internal SD card.
        Tap one of the three buttons to view the data. The screen scolls both horizonally and vertically to 
        allow viewing of all the data. Large data files may take some time to load. The Output Observations 
        tab displays the number of Single and Continuous Mode records stored in the device.</p>

        <p><b>View Single Mode Data File</b>: Displays the single mode observation data.</p>
        <p><b>View Short Continuous Mode Data File</b>: Displays the short records of continuous mode 
        observation data.</p>
        <p><b>View Long Continuous Mode Data File</b>: Displays the long records of continuous mode 
        observation data.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="EarthtideFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Earth Tide Help</b></p>
        <p>The Earth Tide screen allows you to calculate and display earth tide data for a given day, 
        in 10 minute increments. The current date, latitude and longitude are automatically 
        filled in. You can enter a different date, latitude or longitude if you so choose.</p>
        <p><b>Year</b>: Enter the 4 digit year, such as 2014.</p>
        <p><b>Month</b>: Enter a number from 1 - 12.</p>
        <p><b>Day</b>: Enter a number from 1 - 31 (depending on the month and year).</p>
        <p><b>Latitude</b>: Enter the latitude value, in decimal, with north being positive.</p>
        <p><b>Longitude</b>: Enter the longitude value, in decimal, with east being positive.</p>
        <p><b>Elevation</b>: Enter the location\'s elevation, in meters.</p>
        <p><b>Calculate</b>: Calculates and displays the earth tide data.</p>
        <p><b>Obtain Lat/Long from GPS</b>: Retrieves latitude and longitude values from the Android 
        device\'s internal GPS.</p>
        <p><b>Save Data</b>: Not currently implemented.</p>]]></string>

    <!--     Private Fragments -->
    <string name="PrivateParamsFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Private Parameters Help</b></p>
        <p><b>Calibrated</b>: Check this box if the meter is calibrated.</p>
        <p><b>Plates Reversed</b>: Check this box if the plates are reversed.</p>
        <p><b>Save Frequencies</b>: Check this box if you want the beam, levels and temperature 
        frequencies saved with the other observation data in the Output Observation screen.</p>
        <p><b>Test Mode</b>: Check this box to display the following fields 
        during single and continuous mode observations: Beam Frequency, Cross Level Frequency, 
        Long Level Frequency, Temperature Frequency, Temp 0 and Temp B Factor.</p>
        <p><b>Load Calibration Table</b>: Loads a calibration table.</p>
        <p><b>Create Factory Params File</b>: Creates a factory parameters file. This file can be used 
        to restore from if a customer makes changes to one or more factory parameters and later wants to
        return to the factory parameters. This file is not visible to anyone; it can only be created and 
        restored from. The file stores the following parameters: Feedback Gain, Observation Precision, 
        Data Output Rate, Filter Time Constant, Reading Line, Beam Scale, Feedback Scale, Minimum Stop, 
        Maximum Stop, Long Level0, Long LevelA, Long LevelB, Long LevelC, Cross Level0, Cross LevelA, 
        Cross LevelB, Cross LevelC.</p>
        <p><b>Cancel</b>: Exits this screen without saving any changes.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="CCJRCalculateBeamScaleFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Calculate Beam Scale Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to determine and save the meter\'s beam scale value. </p>

        <p><b>50\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 50\%%.</p>
        <p><b>Base Dial Reading</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Base DR -0.500 mGal</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Base DR +0.500 mGal</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>-0.500 Beam Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>+0.500 Beam Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Delta Freq</b>: .</p>
        <p><b>Beam Scale</b>: The calculated beam scale value.</p>
        <p><b>Start Reading</b>: This button tells the meter to start sending gravity data in one second 
        intervals, which will be displayed in the Beam Frequency field. The reading will be 
        terminated when you leave this tab.</p>
        <p><b>Accept</b>: Stores the Beam Scale value in the application database. It can be viewed in 
        the Meter Parameters screen.</p>]]></string>

    <string name="CalculateFeedbackScaleFragment"><![CDATA[<p><b>Calculate Feedback Scale Help</b></p>
        <p>This screen allows you to determine and save the meter\'s feedback scale. <br></p>

        <p><b>10\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 10\%%.</p>
        <p><b>50\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 50\%%.</p>
        <p><b>90\%%</b>: Sets the meter\'s duty cycle to 90\%%.</p>
        <p><b>Current Duty Cycle</b>: The duty cycle value most recently sent to the meter.</p>
        <p><b>New Duty Cycle</b>: Enter a new duty cycle value, between 5 and 98, then tap the Set button.</p>
        <p><b>Set</b>: Sends the New Duty Cycle value to the meter.</p>

        <p><b>Freq row</b>: Enter ?? values in these fields.</p>
        <p><b>5\%% row</b>: Enter ?? values in these fields.</p>
        <p><b>98\%% row</b>: Enter ?? values in these fields.</p>
        <p><b>Delta value row</b>: These values are the 5\%% value - the 98\%% value from the same column.</p>

        <p><b>C/.93</b>: The 0 position Delta value divided by .93.</p>
        <p><b>FDK Scale</b>: The FDK Scale calculated from the above values.</p>
        <p><b>CCNM Factor</b>: The factor calculated from field tests.</p>
        <p><b>Final FDK Scale</b>: The FDK Scale with the CCNM Factor applied to it.</p>

        <p><b>Start Reading</b>: Tap this button to tell the meter to start sending gravity data in one 
        second intervals. The only data from the meter which will be displayed is the Beam Frequency 
        field. The reading will be terminated when you leave this tab.</p>
        <p><b>Clear All</b>: Tap this button to clear all the fields on this screen.</p>
        <p><b>Accept</b>: Tap this button to store the Feedback Scale and all the other fields in the 
        application database. The Feedback Scale can be viewed in the Meter Parameters screen. All the 
        other fields will be recalled the next time this screen is displayed.</p>]]></string>






    <!-- Continuous Observation Params -->
    <string name="latitude">Latitude\nN(+)/S(-)</string>
    <string name="bluetooth_adapter_error_message">There is an error with this device\'s adapter.</string>
    <string name="duty_value_preset_10_percent" translatable="false">10%</string>
    <string name="delete_station_message">You are about to delete the station %1$s.</string>
    <string name="disk_space_warning_message">The device internal memory is %1$.1f%% full. Data loss may result.</string>
    <string name="invalidIntegerRangeAndMultiple">Must be an integer between %1$d and %2$d and a multiple of %3$d</string>
    <string name="before_next_reading_alert_message"><![CDATA[Before taking the next reading,<br/>&#8226; Clamp 
        the beam,<br/>&#8226; Occupy your next station,<br/>&#8226; Level the meter,<br/>&#8226; Unclamp the 
        beam,<br/>&#8226; Press Continue when ready.]]></string>


    <string name="latitude">Latitud\nN(+)/S(-)</string>
    <string name="bluetooth_adapter_error_message">Hay un error con el adaptador Bluetooth de este dispositivo.</string>










</resources>











